Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Additional records 5922
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Additional records
1912-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Joint Board, Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union
5922
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5734533
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5685: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Records 5917 P: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Additional Photographs 5685 P: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Photographs 6214 MB: Herbert Turkel Collection of a Fur Worker's Flesher's Knife, Memorabilia 5922 AV: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Audio-Visual Materials 5922 MB: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Memorabilia
Fur workers--Labor unions.; Leather workers--Labor unions.; Joint Board, Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union.
5734533
- Collective Bargaining Agreements; Constitutions; By-Lavs; Books; Misc. Pamphlets; Anniversary Books; Convention Books; Misc. Booklets. (Box 1)
  - Ocean Leather Contract Signing July 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 25 Silver Anniversary- Fur Chauffeurs Helpers Union Local 122, N.Y., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report Second National Civil Rights Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Second National Civil Rights Conference of the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America AFL-CIO, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report International Civil Rights Conference, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Civil Rights Seminar October 1-3, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cry for Justice, The Failure of Labor Law- A Betrayal of American Workers, and The Leather Workers of Fulton County, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Fur and Leather Workers Union- A Story of Dramatic Struggles and Achievements, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Fur and Leather Workers Union- A Story of Dramatic Struggles and Achievements, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Art From the Bible to Chagall, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Twilight of World Capitalism, Handbook of Civilian Protection, Animals and Man Past Present Future, 1942-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agreement New York Fur Dealers Employers ASSN, Inc. -and- Fur Merchants Employees Union Local 64, 1945-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agreement Fur Merchants Employees Union, Fur Merchants and Employers' Council, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - All For Victory, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Platform Draft, Victory Will be Ours, Drug and Hospital News, Report of the International Executive Board 20th Biennial Convention, 1954-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Furriers Joint Council of New York 25th Anniversary- International Fur Workers Union of the U.S. and Canada Affiliated with A.F. of L., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report International Civil Rights Conference Dec. 1-4, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - North American Furbearers- Their Management, Research and Harvest Status in 1976, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Fur Bearing Mammals of the Soviet Union, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Offprint from Journal of Public Health Policy, Leather Facts, Fur Facts & Figures, 10 Years Joint Board Fur Dressers & Dryers Unions, 1966-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Report of the International Executive Board 18th Biennial Convention, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Rare and Well Done Some Historical Notes on Meats and Meatmen, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - I.F. Stone's Bi-Weekly Nov. 17, 1969- Nov.15, 1971, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Assorted Pamphlets, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Scope and Contents
    Far East Spotlight, The Relationship Between Church and State in the Hungarian People's Republic, People's China Stands for Peace, Facts on the Korean Crisis. Very mixed assortment
  - United States Civil Defense, Endangered Species- Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Energy Nat. Resources and the Environment, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Union Labor Report"; Misc. Publications; FLM Reprints; Clippings; Printing Plate; NLRB Proceedings; Appeals; Thesis; Humane Trapping Report; PAC-Barbaro; Logbook. (Box 2)
  - Collective Labor Agreement between. Associated Fur Manufacturers Inc. and Furriers Joint Council of New York, 1945-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Parliamentary Procedure, Agreement between. Borden, Inc. - Food Division and Film Joint Board and Constitution of the International Fur & Leather Workers Union, 1944-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Constitution Local 122- New York State Bar Association (Box 2, Folder 3)
    For Liza Dubrul from Henry Foner
  - The Search for Peace in Central America and Nixon's Justices Rewrite Our Constitution and Laws, 1976-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    In the Matter of: International Shoe Company, A Division of Interco, Inc. and Joint Council 3, FLM Joint Board Amalgamated Meat Cutters & Butchers Workmen of North America, AFL-CIO
  - Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    In the Matter of: Pocahontas Tanning Co., Division of Howes Leather Co. -and- Joint Council 3, FLM Joint Board, Amalgamated Meat Cutters & Butcher Workmen of North American AFL-CIO et al
  - Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    In the Matter of: Pocahontas Tanning Co., Division of Howes Leather CO. and Joint Council 3, FLM Joint Board, Amalgamated Heat Cutters & Butcher Workmen of North America, AFL-CIO et al
  - Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    In the Matter of International Shoe Company, A Division of Interco, Inc. -and- Joint Council 3, FLM Joint Board, Amalgamated Meat Cutters & Butcher Workmen of North America, AFL-CIO, et al
  - United States Court of Appeals For the Second Circuit 75-6107, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - No. 75-6107 United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brief for Appellant(s) United States Court of Appeals For the District of Columbia Circuit+ Second Circuit, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Ben Gold (Appellant) V. United States of America (Appellee) (First Booklet) United States of America (Appellee) against Benjamin Gold, Irving Potash, Jack Schnelder, Morris Lauber, Joseph Winogradsky, Julius Weil, Samuel Burt, Herman Paul, Al Weiss, Os
  - "S", 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Labor Committee for Barbaro, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A Review of the Structure and Economics of the U.S. Fur Industry, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Court of Appeals State of New York Friends of Animals against Associated Fur Manufacturers Quality Publications, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Report of the Federal Provincial Committee for Humane Trapping 6/81, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - FLM to your Health There is an Art to Successful Retirement, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - AFL-CIO- Community Services and Rehabilitation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Union Labor Report Weekly Newsletter, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Legal-Legislative Reporter News Bulletin, News U.S. Department of Labor Office of Information, Washington, D.C, and State of New York Monthly Bulletin, 1971- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pension Plan Guide Number 268,270,273 and Negotiated Employee Benefit Plans, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Workmen's Compensation Board- Board Decisions and Administrative Ruling, Occupational Mental Health, and FLM Joint Board News, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pension & Welfare News, if Digest, The Nation, 707 Teamster and Labor -UMS, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Washington, Collective Bargaining Report, Better Times Group Health and Welfare news, Facts for Bargaining Consumer Voice, The Machinist, 1960-1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Local 64 News; Member Class File; Various Minutes; Scripts; Joint Board News. (Box 4)
  - Consumer Product Information, Group Insurance Plan, Prints, New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center, Environmental News, Lamps news + Other Docs., 1941- 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local 64 New May+ June, 1955 January 1966, 1955-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Local 64 News, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Joint Board News, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - FLM Joint Board News December 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joint Board News Winter 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Joint Board News Oct. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joint Board News 1963 (Spring, Fall + Summer) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Local 64 News July 1943-April 1956, 1943-1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Local 64 News Jan. '56 to April '56, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Local 64 news May '55 to June '55, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Joint Board News Spring, Summer, Fall 1963 and Dec. 1966, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Property- Minutes for Various Meetings, 1939-1943 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Local 64 New Members Class, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Local 64 New Members Class, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Labor Songs, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Dramatic Group (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Fishermen Script (Les Pine), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Vincent Odds Studio 5552 House 5369} Middletown (Folder 1 of 2), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Vincent Odds Studio 5552 House 5369} Middletown (Folder 1 of 2) Receipts and Song Lyrics (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Ex Board Meetings Record Fur Floor Workers' Union No. 13196, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - AM SEC Executive Board S E Ledger and Constitution International Fur Workers Union, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- District 50 Files; Publisher Correspondence Files; Lipschutz Graphics; McCarthy Meetings (Trial) File; Booklets-Peekskill, Marzani; FCM envelopes; Clippings; Local 110 and 115 Member List; Personal Correspondence to H. Foner; Feb. 1955 F&L Worker. (Box 5)
  - Grove Press-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harper & Row 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pyramid Publications, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Publishing Employees Organizing Committees, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Schwarz 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Some Documents in Spanish
  - Seton 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    An Important Message For Seton Workers- also translated into Spanish
  - C & P 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Most Documents translated into Spanish as well as English
  - Morse 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Documents also translated into Spanish
  - Morse- 1971 NOITU Leaflets (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Documents in Spanish and some in French
  - Morse 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Documents in Spanish + French
  - Tannery Topics, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - District 50 Leaflets 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - District 50 Leaflets 1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Loewengart Co., Inc. Petersburg, W. Va. Allegh 1969-70, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - District 50 Correspondence JC3 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Goldsmith 1966-67, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Walton 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Some documents in Spanish
  - The World of Peggy Lipschutz a portfolio of her graphic works, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - McCarthy Meetings 1/16/53, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Italian Exhibit and Meeting - The Case of Carl Marzani, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Peekskill 1949 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Washington Peace Demonstration Article by Manuel De La Cruz April 24, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Milton Heimlich FACA 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Morocco Visitor To Union June 25, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Nicolella Material, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Fires, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Damascus Pension Newspaper Story, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Taken From Fur + Leather Workers Photograph Collection; 5917p "Anti-Apartheid Demonstrations- April 1985" Bx 1, FF18 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Taken From Fur + Leather Workers Collection; 5917P Bx 1, FF 23, Argentine Trade Union Delegation (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - From the Fur + Leather Workers Photograph Collection Bx1, FF 42, "Bell, John- Testimonial- 3/18/78", 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - From the FLW Photo Collection; 5917P Nina Buchanan Bx 2, FF2, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - From the FLW Photo Collection Bx 2, FF 10, C- (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - From the FLW Photo Collection, 5917) Bx2, FF 28 "Coalition of Labor Union Women", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - From the FLW Photo Collection, 5917P Bx 4, F 19 "Freedman, Ike", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - IFLWU 571-9 P Series I Taken from Bx5 FF 13 Ben Gold, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Taken From IFLWU: 5917P 8x, FF 14, Ben Gold- Photos used or considered for memories (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Taken from the FLW Photo Collection, Bx5 FF #20, Greyhound Demonstration, 11/23/83, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Taken From the FLW Photo Collection, 8x5, FF27, Haitian Rally, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Taken From the FLW Photo Collection, 5917P Bx 16, FF12, Illegal Aliens - Press Conference + Demonstration, 1/73, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Article in Spanish
  - Taken From the FLW Photo Collection, 5917) Bx7 FF # 3134 Labor Movement (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Taken From the FLW Photo Collection, Bx 8 FF#9, Dr. William Levine, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Taken From FLW Photo Collection Bx9, FF # 16, Medicare/Medicaid Rally- 6/83, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Taken From the FLW Photo Collection, 5917P Bx9 FF22, Meisel- Peskin Shop Elections- 10/10/80, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Taken From the IFLWU Photo Collection, Box 9, FF34, Monk Shop- Rabbit Material 8/3/70, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Taken From the IFLWU Photo Collection, Box 9, FF 42, NAARP Conference + Meeting - 5/17/85, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    National Alliance Against Racism + Political Repression
  - Taken From the IFLWU Photo Collection, 5919P Box 10, FF 8, Paul O'Dwyer, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Taken From the IFLWU Photo Collection, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Non-Photographic Temo Series II 5917P (Folder 1 of 2), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Non-Photographic Temo Series II 5917P IFLWU (Folder 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Fur & Leather Worker (Newspaper), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Non Photographic From Bx13 (American Leather Manufacturing Co + Congress of United States- House of Rep.), 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - The Spiral Music 52 No. 749 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Notebook with handwritten music
  - "Photographs A- Bo" Bx1 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Photos
  - Nailers Local # 110 Fishers #115, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Nailers Local # 110 Fishers #115, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 54)